bareknucklepickups.co.uk 2019-12-20

# | Bare Knuckle Pickups

**How we handle your data**

When you use our website, it's our responsibility to protect your personal data and to not misuse any personal information that you provide to us. It is necessary for us to share and store some of the data that you provide us with, in some specific ways, in order for our online store to operate effectively for you, so please take some time to read below as to what we do with your data and how and why we do it.

Bare Knuckle complies fully with all applicable Data Protection and consumer legislation, and we'll treat all your personal information as fully confidential.

**Privacy Policy Key Facts**

  * Some parts of our website require you to provide us with personal data about yourself (such as our online ordering system)

  * Any data which we retain is stored on secure servers

  * Some parts of our website only work if you accept cookies from our website (such as your shopping basket)

  * We do not share your personal data with anyone for marketing purposes

  * We do need to share some of the information that you provide to us with our trusted partners in order to make our online store work correctly (such as sharing your order details with SagePay who process our card payments)

  * We never share any sensitive data or any data which is not specifically required to allow a part of our website to function correctly

  * We have a mailing list which you can opt in or out of which provides periodical newsletters and offers

  * We do not share our mailing list with anyone else for marketing purposes

  * Some features of our site read your IP address in order to provide you with accurate pricing for your region.

  * We do not use any part of our website to obtain your age, date of birth, gender, ethnicity, or any other personal data not relevant to the ordering process on our online store or use of our forum.

  * We store details of orders that you place with Bare Knuckle Pickups indefinitely, for the purpose of easy future reference by you or us and to comply with tax laws

  * We store email history for the purpose of easy reference to details of previous conversations between you and Bare Knuckle Pickups

**Our trusted partners**

We work alongside a very small number other companies in order to provide our online store and they are:

SagePay – providers of our secure card payment processing

Accord Marketing – our website designers / providers

IT Cubed – our IT support and providers of our Email system

Live Chat Inc – providers of our live chat app

We only share data with these companies and no others and that data is only shared when specifically required to allow our online store and email system to function correctly.

We do not share any data with anyone for marketing purposes

**Using our online store**

When using our website to order pickups and accessories from us, or using our online discussion forum, you will need to sign in to our website and provide us with certain personal details about yourself, such as your name, address, email and telephone number. We store this data in order to provide you with a fast and easy service, so that your details are saved if you wish to make further orders in the future and so that any queries with your order can be dealt with efficiently. We store this information on secure servers and do not share any of your personal data with anyone else for marketing or research purposes.

When you make a purchase with us, we use a third party payment processor, SagePay, to handle all of our credit and debit card transactions. As you progress through our checkout process, you will be forwarded to the SagePay secure payment portal to enter your card details. Those card details are handled solely by SagePay and they do not share your card details with us, only basic information about the authorisation status of your purchase. When you are forwarded to SagePay, we do need to share some basic details with them regarding your purchase, such as your name and billing address and the total amount of your order. We do not share any information with them that is not completely necessary to complete your order.

When you sign up with our website, you may be asked if you wish to opt in to our email mailing list. We send out a periodical newsletter, on a roughly monthly basis, which keeps you up to date with the latest news and new products as we release them. We will also from time to time send out special offers and details of competitions. We only retain your email address in our mailing list in order to direct these emails to you, we do not share our mailing list with anyone else for marketing purposes

**Other ways that we interact with you and your data**

Our website uses cookies in order to work correctly. Cookies are small text files which we write onto your computer, which allow us to remember your identity when you load and reload new pages of our website. This is necessary in order to be able to put items into your basket and save them as you progress through the purchase process. You are able to disable the use of cookies, but this will prevent you from being able to use the online store function of our website.

We also read your IP address in order to provide location data that allows us to provide you with the most accurate shipping costs and apply the correct taxation rates for your country.

**Our live chat feature**

Our website has an embedded live chat app, which allows you to speak directly to us in our workshop while you browse our site. When you use this feature, you will be asked to provide your name and email address. This is so that we can identify if you have chatted with us before, in case we need to refer to a previous conversation. The app will also read your IP address to tell us where you are located, so that we can provide you with correct shipping and taxation details when discussing product pricing. This information is not used for marketing and supplying your email address to us here does not add you to our mailing list. We may use your email address in order to contact you if your chat gets cut off, or we need to correct any information that we gave to you during your chat with us.

**Storage of Data**

We retain certain data that you provide us with, as part of your login profile. This includes your name, email address, username and password. This data is stored on secure servers. Staff at Bare Knuckle Pickups have access to your login profile, which is used to check order status, reference previous orders and to assist you in placing new orders. Staff at Bare Knuckle Pickups do not have access to your password.

We retain a history of your orders and emails so that they can be accessed in the future if we need to confirm details of an old order or refer to a query that you have raised with us in the past. All of our order and email history is stored on secure servers.

****Cookies****

**Bareknucklepickups.co.uk uses cookies to keep track of what you have in your basket and to remember you when you return to our site. To make a purchase online at bareknucklepickups.co.uk you need to have all cookies enabled. If cookies aren't enabled on your computer, it will mean that your shopping experience on our website will be limited to browsing and researching; you won't be able to add products to your basket and buy them.**

Cookies are tiny text files stored on your computer when you visit certain web pages. Most web browsers have cookies enabled. Please note that cookies can't harm your computer. We use encrypted information gathered from them to help improve your experience of the site. For example, they help us to identify and resolve errors, or to determine relevant related products to show you when you're browsing.

Our cookies don't store sensitive information such as your name, address or payment details: they simply hold the 'key' that, once you're signed in, is associated with this information. However, if you'd prefer to restrict, block or delete cookies from bareknucklepickups.co.uk, or any other website, you can use your browser to do this. Each browser is different, so check the 'Help' menu of your particular browser (or your mobile phone's handset manual) to learn how to change your cookie preferences.

“Do Not Track” (DNT) is a feature offered by some browsers, with some newer browsers offering it as default. If you enable it, it sends a signal to websites to request that your browsing isn't tracked, for example by third party ad or social networks, or analytic companies. You can opt out of tracking and analytics.

At present no industry-wide uniform standard has been agreed and adopted to determine how DNT requests should be managed, so our website doesn’t currently respond to DNT requests. Until that standard is established, we'll continue to review DNT and other new technologies, but won't respond to DNT requests.

****Our Cookies Policy****

To make full use of the online shopping and personalised features on bareknucklepickups.co.uk, your computer, tablet or mobile phone will need to accept cookies, as we can only provide you with certain personalised features of this website by using them.

****Third Party Cookies****

When you visit bareknucklepickups.co.uk you may notice some cookies that aren't related to Bare Knuckle. If you go on to a web page that contains embedded content, for example from YouTube, you may be sent cookies from these websites. We don't control the setting of these cookies, so we suggest you check the third-party websites for more information about their cookies and how to manage them.

****To Enable Cookies****

If you're not sure of the type and version of web browser you use to access the Internet:

For PCs: Click on 'Help' at the top of your browser window and select the 'About' option

For Macs: With the browser window open, click on the Apple menu and select the 'About' option

****How to Check Cookies are Enabled for PCs****

**Google Chrome**

Click on 'Tools' at the top of your browser window and select Options

Click the 'Under the Hood' tab, locate the 'Privacy' section, and select the 'Content settings' button

Now select 'Allow local data to be set'

**Microsoft Internet Explorer 6.0, 7.0, 8.0**

Click on 'Tools' at the top of your browser window and select 'Internet options' , then click on the 'Privacy' tab

Ensure that your Privacy level is set to Medium or below, which will enable cookies in your browser

Settings above Medium will disable cookies

**Mozilla Firefox**

Click on 'Tools' at the top of your browser window and select Options

Then select the Privacy icon

Click on Cookies, then select 'allow sites to set cookies'

**Safari**

Click on the Cog icon at the top of your browser window and select the 'Preferences' option

Click on 'Security', check the option that says 'Block third-party and advertising cookies'

Click ‘Save'

****How to check cookies are enabled for Macs****

**Microsoft Internet Explorer 5.0 on OSX**

Click on 'Explorer' at the top of your browser window and select 'Preferences' options

Scroll down until you see 'Cookies' under Receiving Files

Select the 'Never Ask' option

**Safari on OSX**

Click on 'Safari' at the top of your browser window and select the 'Preferences' option

Click on 'Security' then 'Accept cookies'

Select the 'Only from site you navigate to'

**Mozilla and Netscape on OSX**

Click on 'Mozilla' or 'Netscape' at the top of your browser window and select the 'Preferences' option

Scroll down until you see cookies under 'Privacy & Security'

Select 'Enable cookies for the originating web site only'

**Opera**

Click on 'Menu' at the top of your browser window and select 'Settings'

Then select 'Preferences', select the 'Advanced' tab

Then select 'Accept cookies' option

**All other browsers**

Please consult your documentation or online help files.

Please note that we're not responsible for the content of external websites.

**Shopping safely on bareknucklepickups.co.uk.**

We hope you enjoy the ease and convenience of shopping on bareknucklepickups.co.uk. Your confidence in our website and your internet security is really important to us, so we've put together some advice to help keep you safe when you shop.

****Passwords****

We do appreciate that remembering passwords can be tricky, but setting effective and secure passwords on all the sites you use is vital in combating possible fraudulent activity using your personal details.

It's best to avoid using the same password for each of your online accounts, because if a criminal gains access to it, all your accounts could be at risk. Multiple passwords keep you safer.

When you set a password, it's a good idea to use a mix of numbers and characters, and something that's very personal to you. Most sites these days will set a minimum number of characters to use, but do avoid using obvious phrases like “password”, or your name, or phone number. It's a good idea to change your passwords on a regular basis, especially for sites you use frequently and which involve financial transactions.

If you ever get a request to reveal your password for an online site, don't respond as legitimate sites and services won't ask you to send them passwords via email. You may be tempted to share passwords with close family, but do keep in mind there's always a risk they could pass information on inadvertently or share it with someone else.

If you ever forget your password you can change it by logging into your Bare Knuckle account. If you get stuck, just e-mail us, sales@bareknucklepickups.co.uk.

For more information on online safety and passwords, there are a number of useful websites such as Get Safe Online, Microsoft Safety & Security, Google good to know.

****Computer security****

Keep yourself safe from malware and viruses with adequate, up to date security on your computer. You can usually download free basic protection from providers such as AVG and McAfee, but choose what works for you. Keep your software switched on and up to date, and make sure that your Windows operating system has the latest Microsoft updates. It's a good idea to run regular scans on your computer.

When you're opening emails, be careful. Don't click on links to download files or open attachments you haven't asked for, or aren't expecting, as they may contain viruses.

Back up all your files so they're available if the worst happens and your computer is infected by a virus.

****Customer Contact****

We'd love you to be among the first to receive exciting offers and news about our products and services. We do this via our newsletter, but only if you would like us to. Your privacy is very important to us which is why we make sure you're always in control of what we do with your personal information.

  * We'll never pass your personal details to anyone outside of Bare Knuckle for them to use for their own marketing purposes

  * We'll only ever use your details to help you make the most of what we have to offer. That means things like:

  * Tips and guidance to help you get the best out of your products

  * News to help you make informed choices in the things you buy

  * Details of new products and services

  * Special offers

  * Or simply, to get your feedback

We will make sure our contact with you is relevant based on the information you give us.

You can opt out at any time. If you do ‘opt out' of receiving this information you could miss out on offers and news.

We'll always comply with the Data Protection Act 1998 and all other relevant legislation. You can see how we're doing this by reading our full Privacy Policy.

Please do let us know if your details change so that we can continue to stay in touch.

****Transaction security****

Bareknucklepickups.co.uk is a secure website. We realise how important it is to securely store any information that you provide and Bareknucklepickups.co.uk maintains the highest levels of security. Our site uses high-level SSL encryption technology, the most advanced security software currently available for online transactions. You can therefore rest assured that we take the privacy and security of your payment and personal details very seriously.

You can tell whether a page is secure as 'https' will replace the 'http' at the front of the “[ _bareknucklepickups.co.uk_](http://bareknucklepickups.co.uk/)” in your browser address window. A small locked padlock will also appear in the bottom bar of your browser window.

****Using WiFi in public places****

Using an unsecured network in a public place can be risky as unauthorised people may try to intercept anything you're doing online. We recommend you only connect to secure wireless networks that you trust, and to always be aware of the risks associated with using public WiFi.

****Phishing****

Phishing is the practice of tricking someone into giving confidential information. Examples include falsely claiming to be a legitimate company when sending an e-mail to a user, in an attempt to get the user to send private information that will be used for identity theft and fraud.

We'll never ask you to send any personal details via email. If we require such details, for security reasons we'll ask you to contact us by phone. Should you receive an email claiming to be from bareknucklepickups.co.uk requesting this kind of information, please don't respond, but do let us know about it.
